So let's get started with order ordering things.
所以让我们开始订购东西吧。
When do we use the endings for numbers like you probably know first.
我们什么时候使用你可能首先知道的数字的结尾。
Why do we sometimes say 1.
为什么我们有时会说 1。
Why do we sometimes say 1 s t or F I R S T.
为什么我们有时会说 1 s t 或 F I R S T。
OK well if we have one thing then we don't need to use this.
好吧，如果我们有一件事，那么我们就不需要使用它。
OK.
好的。
We don't need to use that.
我们不需要使用它。
We just have one thing.
我们只有一件事。
So we say I have one apple OK.
所以我们说我有一个苹果。
There are two people we're just counting.
我们只是在数两个人。
OK but if things go in order.
好的，但如果一切顺利的话。
If there is a sequence and we're focused on the sequence that means this one and then this one and then
如果有一个序列，我们专注于这个序列，然后这个序列，然后这个序列，然后这个序列
this one and then this one and then this one there's a sequence then often we will use this.
这个然后这个然后这个有一个序列然后我们经常会使用这个。
The endings for numbers we use it very simply for days in the month all the way up to thirty first which
数字的结尾我们非常简单地使用它来表示一个月中的几天一直到第三十个
is the longest a month can be the thirty first.
最长的一个月可以是三十第一。
So things in sequence not everything but often things in sequence.
所以事情的顺序不是一切，而是事情往往是按顺序排列的。
Could you say my thirty first birthday.
你能说我三十岁的生日吗？
Yes.
是的。
Yes you can.
是的你可以。
Thirty first birthday because birthdays are in sequence.
第三十个生日，因为生日是按顺序排列的。
You can also say that you're thirty three years old.
你也可以说你已经三十三岁了。
You can certainly say that thirty three years old but you can say it's your thirty first birthday because
你当然可以说三十三岁，但你可以说这是你三十一岁的生日，因为
that's in sequence.
这是按顺序的。
What else goes in order like that.
还有什么是这样的。
When else might we use this sort of language in sequence.
我们什么时候可以按顺序使用这种语言。
Well if we have something and then we get rid of it or we get another thing of the same type then we
好吧，如果我们有一些东西，然后我们摆脱它，或者我们得到另一个相同类型的东西，那么我们
can start to use this because we have one and then we have another of the same kind of thing.
可以开始使用它，因为我们有一个，然后我们有另一个相同的东西。
It's a kind of sequence so let's say I buy a bike by the company maybe you know the company track it's
这是一种顺序，所以假设我从公司购买了一辆自行车，也许你知道公司跟踪它
a bike company let's say I buy a track I have one track bike OK and I like it.
一家自行车公司，假设我买了一条轨道，我有一辆轨道自行车，我喜欢它。
So I decide well this one was cheap so I'll buy another one.
所以我决定这个很便宜，所以我会再买一个。
Now I have two track bikes.
现在我有两辆轨道自行车。
Well this one this one tried to draw a bike.
那么这个这个这个试图画一辆自行车。
Oh my God this is a terrible this bicycle.
哦，天哪，这辆自行车太可怕了。
This one is my first track bike and this one.
这是我的第一辆轨道自行车和这辆。
Let's just say there's another one here.
假设这里还有一个。
This one is my two second.
这是我的两秒钟。
Now I know that you probably know this but I just want to be very clear when we use it and when we don't
现在我知道你可能知道这一点，但我只想非常清楚我们什么时候使用它，什么时候不使用它
usually if it is a sequence of things maybe it's my third bike and my second track bike that's possible.
通常，如果是一系列事情，那可能是我的第三辆自行车和第二辆履带自行车。
Third bike second track bike totally fine.
第三辆自行车第二辆轨道自行车完全没问题。
Totally fine.
完全没问题。
Let's just read through these very quickly just so that you know the pronunciation and then I want to
让我们快速阅读这些内容，以便您知道发音，然后我想
talk about the floors of a building.
谈论建筑物的楼层。
OK.
好的。
This one twenty first.
这个二十一。
This one 30 second 30 second.
这个30秒30秒。
This one third this one.
这个三分之一这个。
Seventy fourth.
七十四。
This one sixty fifth.
这一点六十五分。
This one's tough to save.
这个好难救
Fifth fifth sixty fifth.
五五六十五。
Another one that's tough to say is the next one.
另一个很难说的是下一个。
One hundred and six.
一百零六。
Six.
六。
You have to actually say six.
您实际上必须说六个。
And then with a t h sound.
然后发出 t h 的声音。
Sixty six sixty six.
六六六十六。
One hundred and six.
一百零六。
Forty seventh forty seventh seven seven.
四十七 四十七 七 七。
Adding t h eighty eighth.
加上八十八。
So this one we have a kind of ay ay ay.
所以这个我们有一种ay ay ay。
We don't say eight.
我们没有说八。
Like that we just say eight and we stop the voice.
就像那样，我们只说八，然后停止声音。
Eight.
八。
OK.
好的。
Nine nine nine.
九九九。
So when it has t h we do have to make that sound.
所以当它有 t h 时，我们必须发出那个声音。
And what about this one if it's on an even ten 10th 20th 30th 40 50 if this is 50 50.
如果这是 50 50，那么如果它在偶数 10 10 20 30 40 50 上呢？
If fiftieth OK.
如果第五十行。
Now it gets a little different if it's teens but those are all the same except for twelve.
现在如果是十几岁，情况会有所不同，但除了十二岁外，其他都是一样的。
So this one is twelve twelve twelve.
所以这个是十二十二十二。
It's difficult twelfth than the other ones are all the same.
比其他的都难十二分。
13th 14th 15th 16th all of them are T H and you just say the number thirteen and then.
13th 14th 15th 16th 所有这些都是 T H，你只需说出数字 13 然后。
Except you have to be careful about this and this you gotta watch out for that pronunciation.
除了你必须小心这个，你必须注意那个发音。
This is death.
这是死亡。
If it's a ten then we use it.
如果是十，那么我们就使用它。
If it's a team then we use thirtieth 40 if fiftieth 13th 14th 15th 15th and the 15th are very different
如果是一个团队，那么我们使用第 30 40 如果第 50 13 14 15 15 和 15 非常不同
but it's the tone that we also have to pay attention to.
但这也是我们要注意的语气。
So in a building when you're describing the floor in the building because they're in sequence going
因此，在建筑物中，当您描述建筑物中的楼层时，因为它们按顺序排列
up they are in sequence going up then we're going to use these endings as the floor names.
up 它们依次上升，然后我们将使用这些结尾作为楼层名称。
So you have a tall building here.
所以你在这里有一座高楼。
OK and maybe this is the 30 second 30 second floor the 30 second floor the 50 second floor the 50 second
好的，也许这是 30 秒 30 二楼 30 二楼 50 二楼 50 秒
floor.
地面。
So once you know the endings and you know how to say them it should be easy but just pay attention to
所以一旦你知道结局并且你知道如何说它们应该很容易，但只要注意
the fact that these numbers become the names of those things.
这些数字成为这些事物的名称。
And if we say how old are you.
如果我们说你几岁。
I'm thirty three.
我三十三岁。
That's not the name of your age right.
那不是你这个年龄的名字吧。
That's not the name of your birthday.
那不是你生日的名字。
But if we say it's my thirty third birthday or my fortieth birthday that's kind of the name of your
但如果我们说这是我的三十三岁生日或四十岁生日，这就是你的名字
birthday isn't it.
生日是不是。
The name of your birthday.
你生日的名字。
So it helps us to name things and specify exactly which thing we're talking about.
因此，它可以帮助我们命名事物并准确说明我们正在谈论的事物。
Which floor you're going to I'm going to the eighty second floor.
你去哪一层，我去八十二楼。
Wow that's pretty high up eighty second floor.
哇，八十二楼好高啊。
Cool.
凉爽的。
You live very high up.
你住得很高。
OK.
好的。
Or the 13th floor and if if you go into many buildings in Western countries you will not see a 13th
或者 13 楼，如果你走进西方国家的许多建筑物，你不会看到 13 楼
floor on the buttons in the elevator.
电梯按钮上的地板。
Why not.
为什么不。
Because 13 in a lot of Western countries is an unlucky number.
因为在很多西方国家，13 是一个不吉利的数字。
It's a bad number.
这是一个糟糕的数字。
So you won't see a 13th floor for that reason.
所以你不会因为这个原因看到 13 楼。
In many places many places not all but many.
在很多地方很多地方不是全部，而是很多。
All right.
好的。
That's pretty simple.
这很简单。
I realize hopefully it's clear.
我意识到希望它很清楚。